Charles Brown

405-623-1948 | CA.Brown.OK@gmail.com | Lexington, OK

Summary

Entry-level front-end web developer with strong multi-industry experience in time-sensitive, complex problem solving and a bias for action in continuous improvement. Dedicated to the building and ongoing maintenance of reliable and efficient industrial/digital systems that provide positive results.

Skills

HTML5, CSS, WordPress, Javascript,

Experience

Amazon Warehouse | Oklahoma City, OK Fulfillment Associate | 08/2021 - Present

- Launched Oklahoma's first Traditional Non-Sort Amazon facility while in the Stow department and quickly ascended to the top 10% of the Stow department by rate
- Excelled in the Learning Department as a Powered Industrial Truck Ambassador by using communication skills to train newly on-boarded associates in the safe operation of powered equipment
- Reduced safety incidents by 10% by collaborating in a curriculum re-tooling
- Coached a team of 6-12 associates on quality, rate, and safety by using KPI tracking software and staff organization to insure a high-quality customer experience
- Increased the rate and efficiency of Amazon Robotics floor5% by completing Amnesty Floor Monitor training and utilizing fast-paced problem-solving skills

Del Real Foods | Moore, OK Maintenance Technician | 03/2020 - 04/2021

- Increased production by 50% during peak periods by upgrading commercial kitchen equipment using rapid prototyping and bias for action
- Reduced downtime by 15% by maintaining and repairing production equipment and facilities using electrical troubleshooting skills
- Lead a kitchen team of 4-10 employees in the safe and clean production of food products at an industrial scale
- Collaborated with specialists and contractors in upgrading/repair of compressed ammonia freezer systems

Centek Group | Oklahoma City, OK Maintenance Technician | 08/2013 - 03/2020

- Increased production and capacity output by over 25% while reducing cost and staffing needs by utilizing Lean
 Implementation manufacturing principles and rapid prototyping to improve the fabrication process by collaborating with
 peers on the successful redesign of the production line
- Maintained a full inventory of materials needed to maintain both production and facilities by utilizing a Maintenance Management System to reduce excessive inventory
- Reduced tooling costs by over 50% by collaborating with plant engineers in the design of in-house built production tooling and utilizing fabrication skills along with in-process design improvements

Education

Correlation One | Oklahoma City, OK Software Development | 09/2023

- Selected to participate in a 5-month Software Development training program sponsored by Amazon Career Choice that utilized Codio in learning Advanced HTML/CSS, UI/UX Design, frameworks based in Javascript, and WordPress CMS
- · Solved business problems using case-based, real-world data
- · Developed data literacy in front-end development

Francis Tuttle Technology Center | Oklahoma City, OK AC/DC Electrical Maintenace | 09/2017

• Certificate of completion in AC/DC Electrical Maintenance and Motor Controls